<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bay Area Real Estate Video Blog with Greg McDaniel</title>
    <description>Our mission at McDaniel Callahan TEAM is to be your best resource for Bay Area real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The McDaniel Callahan TEAM, your professional Bay Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 12:37:20 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 12:37:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Ways Buyers Can Prepare for Closing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Rdz_pb8r84E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have had your offer accepted and are on your way to the closing table, there are still a few things you need to take care of. Today I will highlight four ways to prepare for closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Looking to buy a Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buyandsellalamodanvillehomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Bay Area homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling Your Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcma.com/api_widget/6757802779fbc05a66bfd8f78d617a92/show?post_url=cloudcma.com&amp;amp;source_url=ua&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Use our home evaluation tool.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens at the closing table when you’re buying a house?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I will go over what to expect, as well as a few crucial do’s and don’ts to follow as you move through the process. Keeping all of this information in mind will be very important in making sure you get the keys to your new home with no problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Schedule the closing.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of the time, your agent will coordinate with all parties involved to schedule the closing for you. That said, it is still important to make sure this gets done. Also, make sure you take your time at the closing table. Don’t try to squeeze in the meeting over your lunch hour, because there will be a lot of critical documents to look over. I recommend taking a half-day to make sure you’ve got adequate time to review all papers carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Do a final walk-through.&lt;/strong&gt; As a buyer, you have the right to go through the home within five days of closing and make sure that it’s still in an acceptable condition. You are entitled to take possession of the home in the exact state it was in when your offer on the property was accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=ANY CHANGES TO YOUR DEBT-TO-INCOME RATIO WILL POSE A HUGE THREAT TO THE SUCCESS OF YOUR HOME PURCHASE.%20http://localhost:4000/4-ways-buyers-can-prepare-for-closing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“ANY CHANGES TO YOUR DEBT-TO-INCOME RATIO WILL POSE A HUGE THREAT TO THE SUCCESS OF YOUR HOME PURCHASE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Take all the documents with you to closing.&lt;/strong&gt; If any issues arise, you will be able to provide any and all necessary paperwork needed to resolve those problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Keep in mind the things that could go wrong with your deal.&lt;/strong&gt; There are a few pitfalls you may encounter. This includes things like the bank pulling out at the last minute or an unexpected lien showing up, but the greatest problem that could occur is actually within the buyer’s control. Any changes to your debt-to-income ratio will pose a huge threat to the success of your home purchase. This means that you need to make sure you put off any major purchases, especially those made on credit, until after closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many more things to keep in mind before proceeding to closing when buying or selling a home. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 15:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-ways-buyers-can-prepare-for-closing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-ways-buyers-can-prepare-for-closing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bay Area Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways to Back out of a Home Purchase Without Being a Jerk</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ni7JxqsEI9s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it ever okay to back out of a deal? Yes. Today, I’ll highlight three examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Looking to buy a Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buyandsellalamodanvillehomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Bay Area homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling Your Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcma.com/api_widget/6757802779fbc05a66bfd8f78d617a92/show?post_url=cloudcma.com&amp;amp;source_url=ua&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Use our home evaluation tool.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backing out of a home purchase can make you seem like a big jerk, but it doesn’t have to. There are three ways you can get out of a deal without coming off as rude:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. If you’re unhappy with the physical inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; No matter how excited you were to purchase a home in the beginning, an unsavory inspection report can be a sure way to burst that bubble. If a home just isn’t right for you, or has problems you just can’t look past, it’s often best to walk away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. If your purchase is contingent upon the sale of your current home.&lt;/strong&gt; If your current home doesn’t go under contract within the designated time frame, you have no obligation to go through with the purchase. This contingency can act as your “Get Out of Jail Free” card, and save you from juggling two mortgages at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF A HOME JUST ISN’T RIGHT FOR YOU, OR HAS PROBLEMS YOU JUST CAN’T LOOK PAST, IT’S OFTEN BEST TO WALK AWAY.%20http://localhost:4000/3-ways-to-back-out-of-home-purchase.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF A HOME JUST ISN’T RIGHT FOR YOU, OR HAS PROBLEMS YOU JUST CAN’T LOOK PAST, IT’S OFTEN BEST TO WALK AWAY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. If the homeowners association documents raise a red flag.&lt;/strong&gt; When you purchase a home in a homeowners association (or HOA), you’ll receive a huge stack of documents outlining the rules, regulations, and fees that will apply to you if you choose to go through with the purchase. We want to see what kind of finances the HOA has, how the board is, what the facility is like and if it will need any maintenance down the road, and also if you as a homeowner will have to put up a large chunk of money to add to reserves if there is a special assessment that is called. I highly recommend that you review these documents carefully before committing yourself to living in an HOA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-ways-to-back-out-of-home-purchase.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-ways-to-back-out-of-home-purchase.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bay Area Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Market Update for the Alamo/Danville Area</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/k9BPA3zkdEE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a buyer’s market in the Alamo/Danville area, but as a buyer, you still need to be patient and be smart when you buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Looking to buy a Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buyandsellalamodanvillehomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Bay Area homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling Your Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcma.com/api_widget/6757802779fbc05a66bfd8f78d617a92/show?post_url=cloudcma.com&amp;amp;source_url=ua&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Use our home evaluation tool.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am joined by my father Terry McDaniel to share the latest news from our Alamo/Danville market. &lt;strong&gt;Right now, the numbers tell us it is a great time to buy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Alamo, there are 38 homes available for sale, and the median asking price for these homes is $2.15 million. There are also 27 pending properties, which is almost ideal because you usually want to see a 1:1 ratio between available properties and pending properties. The median price of these pending homes is $1.7 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These stats indicate that the lower part of the market is the most active, while the upper part is starting to see homes with price adjustments of $50,000, $75,000, and even $100,000. This kind of thing is typical when interest rates are rising, so be patient and be smart when you buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember — &lt;strong&gt;you only make money when you buy; you don’t make money when you sell.&lt;/strong&gt; There are a number of properties that have not hit the market yet, and prices are not rising at the crazy rate that they previously were. If you are a buyer, these facts should help you during your negotiations with sellers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Alamo, there are about 5,500 homes in total. In Danville, there are about twice as many. To find the home that is right for you, it is very important that you calibrate for each price range and move in $250,000 increments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=MAKE SURE YOU PICK THE VERY BEST PROPERTY YOU CAN BUY.%20http://localhost:4000/a-quick-market-update-for-alamodanville.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“MAKE SURE YOU PICK THE VERY BEST PROPERTY YOU CAN BUY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, make sure you plot out the houses. The west side of Alamo, for instance, is going to be more expensive as far as lots go. The lot values in that area are between $1.3 million and $1.5 million, which is an increase compared to when they were worth between $900,000 and $1.2 million four years ago. Can they continue to go up in value? Absolutely. Will they continue to go up in value? Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home values can rise and fall, but in 10 to 20 years, you will be glad you bought a property now. A leveraged asset in residential real estate is a great way to accommodate your family’s future. &lt;strong&gt;There are many ways to buy property, so don’t assume you can’t afford it.&lt;/strong&gt; If you talk to us, we can make it happen for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in discussing the market further with my father or you would like to know the value of your home, you can reach him by phone at (925) 838-4300.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other questions for me or you have any real estate needs at all, please feel free to reach out to me. I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 10:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-quick-market-update-for-alamodanville.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-quick-market-update-for-alamodanville.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bay Area Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Much Do You Pay Uncle Sam in Property Taxes? </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/F4NohVJO3f0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’ll give you an idea of what you should expect to pay in property taxes and how you’ll pay that amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Looking to buy a Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buyandsellalamodanvillehomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Bay Area homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling Your Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcma.com/api_widget/6757802779fbc05a66bfd8f78d617a92/show?post_url=cloudcma.com&amp;amp;source_url=ua&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Use our home evaluation tool.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much money do you need to pay Uncle Sam when it comes to your property taxes? Let’s find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say your home is worth $200,000 and your tax rate is 1.5%. This means on an annual basis, you’d pay $3,000 (or $250 per month). There can be additional taxes, fees, and assessments added to this number, so double-check with your tax assessor to make sure you’re paying the right amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have an idea of what you’ll have to pay, you need to figure out how you’ll pay it. This part is actually pretty simple. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re paying a mortgage, you’ll most likely have an impound account set up with your lender.&lt;/strong&gt; Every single month, your lender (or whoever holds your note) will collect money out of that account for insurance purposes or property tax purposes. They’ll then put that money into an escrow account so it can be paid when it’s due.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOUR MORTGAGE PAYMENT AND YOUR PROPERTY TAX PAYMENT ARE SEPARATE.%20http://localhost:4000/how-much-do-you-pay-uncle-sam-in.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOUR MORTGAGE PAYMENT AND YOUR PROPERTY TAX PAYMENT ARE SEPARATE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is important to note because a lot of people think that they pay their property taxes along with their mortgage. In reality, these payments are separate from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you don’t have a mortgage, it’s your responsibility to make your property tax payment to your tax assessor or the tax board.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about property taxes, you have any other real estate questions, or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in our market, don’t hesitate to call or email me anytime. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 10:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-much-do-you-pay-uncle-sam-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-much-do-you-pay-uncle-sam-in.html</guid>
        
        <category>Property Taxes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fun in the Bay: Summer 2018 Edition</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jKhKNwRC3s0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time for our Fun in the Bay: Summer 2018 Edition. There are some great events happening in our area this year, and I can’t wait to share them with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Looking to buy a Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buyandsellalamodanvillehomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Bay Area homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling Your Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcma.com/api_widget/6757802779fbc05a66bfd8f78d617a92/show?post_url=cloudcma.com&amp;amp;source_url=ua&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Use our home evaluation tool.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m dressed for summer because it’s time to talk about Fun in the Bay: Summer Edition. Here are a few great events that you should check out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Danville Area Community Harvest.&lt;/strong&gt; The harvest takes place on May 5 from 10 a.m. to 1 p.m. Meet at the Danville Park and Ride right next to the 680 freeway. We will be harvesting backyard fruits for donations to local soup kitchens, food pantries, shelters, and the food bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvests typically take about three hours, and you’ll travel no more than 25 miles from the starting location. We will have all of the necessary equipment, including buckets, picking poles, ladders, clippers, and crates with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure that you wear closed-toe shoes and appropriate clothing for the weather. You may also want to consider bringing water, a snack, a hat or sunglasses, gardening gloves, and a brown bag to take some fruit home for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about The Urban Farmers at www.theurbanfarmers.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE HOPE YOU HAVE A GREAT SUMMER AND ENJOY THESE EVENTS!%20http://localhost:4000/fun-in-bay-summer-2018-edition.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE HOPE YOU HAVE A GREAT SUMMER AND ENJOY THESE EVENTS!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How Weird Street Faire.&lt;/strong&gt; The theme this year is The Disco Ball Inferno! The festival season starts on May 6 at 2:22 p.m. (how weird!) in downtown San Francisco at Howard and 2nd street. Join thousands of people in colorful costumes from around the world who have come together to celebrate peace, creativity, and Weirdness. There will be dancing in the streets and 10 stages of great music, along with fantastic foods, unique vendors, and visionary art. This whole Faire is dedicated to inspiring creativity. You can learn more at HowWeird.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The San Francisco Beer and Music Festival.&lt;/strong&gt; Starting at 6 p.m. on June 2 in Union Square, you’ll be able to enjoy the sunset and party into the night. You can try unlimited samples of over 10 craft beers, wine, and spirits. There will also be live bands and a deejay to get the crowd on their feet. There will also be plenty of food. You can learn more at SanFrancisco-BeerFestival.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Music in the Park—The Big Jangle.&lt;/strong&gt; Go to Danville Oak Hill Park on June 23 from 6 to 8 p.m. There will be music by The Big Jangle and a Tom Petty and the Heartbreakers tribute band. Bring some chairs, blankets, and coolers and enjoy a harmonious evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you have time to check out these awesome events. As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/fun-in-bay-summer-2018-edition.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/fun-in-bay-summer-2018-edition.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bay Area Summer Fun</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Choose Positivity?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JodG_Xd7M9M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice to be kind is in your hands. It isn’t always easy, but I’d like to challenge you to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Looking to buy a Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buyandsellalamodanvillehomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Bay Area homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling Your Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcma.com/api_widget/6757802779fbc05a66bfd8f78d617a92/show?post_url=cloudcma.com&amp;amp;source_url=ua&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Use our home evaluation tool.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all encountered toxic people, but what’s the best way to handle these individuals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start out, let me tell you a story. I was recently making a few follow-up calls when I encountered a gentleman who seemed to be generally angry with life. &lt;strong&gt;A lot of things were said in the conversation that I could have reacted negatively to, but I decided to do something against that impulse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gentleman was upset at me having called his elderly mother, who had expressed interest in selling her home with me. He insinuated I was harassing her, which obviously wasn’t my intention. But instead of reacting with a negative attitude, I defended my position and asked him to help me understand his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I allowed the gentleman to explain his position, then de-escalated the situation by expressing empathy and solidarity.&lt;/strong&gt; I offered to take him out of my database, apologized for the situation at hand, and ended the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU HAVE THE CHOICE TO REMAIN POSITIVE.%20http://localhost:4000/why-choose-positivity.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU HAVE THE CHOICE TO REMAIN POSITIVE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I still felt slightly shaken up by what had just happened, I was able to step away from the situation knowing I chose not to let it get out of hand. We have this same choice in every interaction we’re a part of. You can and should always choose kindness. People may push our buttons, but you always have the choice to remain positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always remember that &lt;strong&gt;we have no way of knowing what another person is going through, so try to avoid falling into negative behavior.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this isn’t related to our usual topics, but I do think it’s important. So, take this message and apply it in your daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, would like more information, or need help with any of your real estate needs, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 11:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-choose-positivity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-choose-positivity.html</guid>
        
        <category>Traits of Success</category>
        
        <category>The McDaniel Callahan Team</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Check Out This Great House in Concord </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pt_CDaNBQYc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out this awesome property in Concord. The house is under contract, but it’s so great I wanted to share it with you anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Looking to buy a Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buyandsellalamodanvillehomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Bay Area homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling Your Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcma.com/api_widget/6757802779fbc05a66bfd8f78d617a92/show?post_url=cloudcma.com&amp;amp;source_url=ua&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Use our home evaluation tool.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to take you on a tour of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trulia.com/p/ca/concord/2427-sycamore-ave-concord-ca-94520--2083283947&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one of our properties&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a heads up that the sale is pending on this property; we sold it in seven days for 100% of the listing price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a 3-bed, 1-bath, 1,200 sq. ft. home with one of the best kitchens I’ve seen in a long time. The house is located right in downtown Concord. &lt;strong&gt;You can walk to Mount Diablo High School or walk to downtown Concord for food or events.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a quiet, one-way street, and you’re right next to the John Muir Medical Center as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the video above for a complete tour of the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did take out a fence to open up the front yard and give the house a new look. The interior features hardwood floors, a nice, open floor plan, and a great fireplace. Make sure you watch the video to check out that kitchen, which even comes with a prep sink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE SELLER MADE SOME GREAT UPGRADES TO THE PROPERTY, INCLUDING CONVERTING THE GARAGE INTO A MASTER SUITE.%20http://localhost:4000/check-out-this-great-house-in-concord.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE SELLER MADE SOME GREAT UPGRADES TO THE PROPERTY, INCLUDING CONVERTING THE GARAGE INTO A MASTER SUITE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The garage was converted into a great master bedroom suite with vaulted ceilings and a skylight. The backyard is big enough to play an NFL football game, and there is a side yard with a well, which is great for gardeners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also an outdoor structure that could be used as an office, as well as two structures for storage. &lt;strong&gt;You could easily install a pool in the backyard next to the orange trees without losing a lot of space.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned earlier, this house is currently under contract. Stay tuned for more great properties, or reach out to me if you would like us to sell your home as fast as we sold this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 11:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/check-out-this-great-house-in-concord.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/check-out-this-great-house-in-concord.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bay Area Homes For Sale</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stop Earning a Paycheck and Start Earning Wealth </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2NM_rKrplqc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By joining The McDaniel Callahan Real Estate Team, powered by eXp Realty, you will have the chance to do more than earn a paycheck; you will build wealth for you and your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Looking to buy a Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buyandsellalamodanvillehomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Bay Area homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling Your Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcma.com/api_widget/6757802779fbc05a66bfd8f78d617a92/show?post_url=cloudcma.com&amp;amp;source_url=ua&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Use our home evaluation tool.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you join our team and eXp Realty, you will have the opportunity to build wealth for you and your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you get when you join eXp Realty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, there are three different ways to make revenue just by selling real estate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;indent&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting your commission. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you build a team, get a part of their deals as they do them until they cap out at $16,000. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stock—eXp is a publicly traded company, so their stock is very valuable and always rising. You get stock when you close a deal and when you bring on a team member. If you decide to go to Icon status, your $16,000 cap is given back to you at the end of the year in company stocks, so basically, you are only paying them $5,000 in commission splits for the entire year. I can go over how this works in more detail on our one-on-one call.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eXp Realty gives you 25 to 35 live hours of training every single week.&lt;/strong&gt; You also have access to their digital campus, so you can get things done in a snap. I have been thoroughly impressed with how client-centric this company is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a small brokerage, you can come on over and keep your culture, your brand, your people, and your brick-and-mortar office. All you have to do is add “powered by eXp” on the bottom right. Again, we can talk about that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a few perks of joining eXp Realty. &lt;strong&gt;What exactly do you get when you join The McDaniel Callahan Team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, you will get access to our 90-day jumpstart system. Here’s what that looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;indent&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’ll start with a system called “36 to Life” with my good friend, Hank Avink. I coach with this system too, but I may not coach your session depending on scheduling. “36 to Life” is usually $300, but with us, you’ll only pay $36 for a month long program. That will be the best $36 you’ve spent in your life. I guarantee that if you don’t like it, you’ll get your money back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rockstar Conversations is an eight-week self-guided program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rockstar Mastermind takes place every Monday morning. Matt and I get together at 9 a.m. to coach and train on a specific topic or issue. This information is hyperlocal to our area.
After that, we’ll move you to the E.R.S. Livestream with Jeff Cohn. **Jeff is a real estate powerhouse based out of Omaha, Nebraska, and he has opened his coaching sessions up for free to all of our team members** on Wednesdays and Fridays at 8 a.m. Pacific Standard time. Jeff’s team did 750 deals last year and, as of this recording, he’s on track to do 1,000 deals in 2018. You can learn a lot from him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=SCHEDULE A CALL WITH ME TODAY TO SEE IF THIS IS THE RIGHT FIT FOR YOU.%20http://localhost:4000/stop-earning-paycheck-and-start-earning.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“SCHEDULE A CALL WITH ME TODAY TO SEE IF THIS IS THE RIGHT FIT FOR YOU.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt and I will also do monthly Q&amp;amp;A calls and potentially bring in guests to cover specific topics. You can also book time on my personal calendar if there is anything you want to talk to me about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also have access to any of our team’s products, such as the Rockstar Conversations, our high-tech, high-touch farming product (eight to 12 hours of farming content), and The Introvert’s Guide to Real Estate Success. If you don’t like being out in front of people, this is a guide we put together with Dr. Debra Dupree, a psychologist here in San Diego. She breaks down how you can be an introvert and succeed and thrive in real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next upcoming product is called “How to Find Your Next Client Using Facebook Live.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in learning more about this opportunity, go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://calendly.com/mcdaniel-44/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BookMcDaniel.com&lt;/a&gt; to book a 30-minute talk with me to see if this is a good fit for you. If it is, great! If not, that’s fine, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to give you the opportunity to do more than earn a paycheck in real estate. I want to help you start building wealth for you and your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do decide to do this, I’ll run some numbers to show you how this compounds in a short amount of time. You can literally get mailbox money by adding five, 10, 15, or 25 people from anywhere in the country to your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://calendly.com/mcdaniel-44/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BookMcDaniel.com&lt;/a&gt; to schedule a 30-minute talk with me. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 14:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/stop-earning-paycheck-and-start-earning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/stop-earning-paycheck-and-start-earning.html</guid>
        
        <category>The McDaniel Callahan Team Careers</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Exciting Announcement From the McDaniel Callahan Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xVI91MlcTmA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the launch of a new partnership. Stay tuned for details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Looking to buy a Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buyandsellalamodanvillehomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Bay Area homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling Your Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcma.com/api_widget/6757802779fbc05a66bfd8f78d617a92/show?post_url=cloudcma.com&amp;amp;source_url=ua&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Use our home evaluation tool.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got big news for you and for us today. We are ecstatic to announce the fact that we’ve made a shift over to a new brokerage called exp Realty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the fastest-growing national brokerage in the country. They went from 3,000 agents to over 6,500 in just the last year. eXp Realty is a tech-based real estate brokerage that has so many different amazing tools that will allow us to help you get your home seen and sold faster and for higher prices. &lt;strong&gt;The technology and the personnel over at eXp have been simply amazing.&lt;/strong&gt; They have been able to get us everything we want and need in a timely manner and it’s a great environment to be around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to make sure and let you guys know why we shifted. The future is digital, it’s remote, and a lot of the brick and mortar businesses won’t be around. The mindset of the average human will be digitally-based (if it isn’t already), so we took the leap ahead of time so that we can help grow our team nationally and locally here in Alamo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=OUR TEAM IS EXTREMELY EXCITED FOR OUR MOVE TO EXP REALTY.%20http://localhost:4000/an-exciting-announcement-from-mcdaniel.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“OUR TEAM IS EXTREMELY EXCITED FOR OUR MOVE TO EXP REALTY.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re an agent and want to learn about what value we can bring to you, we have a laundry list of goodness to share with you to help you put more money in your pockets.&lt;/strong&gt; There are three revenue streams with eXp Realty (and you get stock since they are a publicly traded company).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us about joining our team or need any assistance in reaching your real estate goals, feel free to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. Also, if you are interested in joining our team or learning more about why we switched, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://calendly.com/mcdaniel-44/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.bookmcdaniel.com&lt;/a&gt;. I would love to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 16:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-exciting-announcement-from-mcdaniel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/an-exciting-announcement-from-mcdaniel.html</guid>
        
        <category>The McDaniel Callahan Team</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What 10 Terms Should All First-Time Homebuyers Know?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zqeMokONc0U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 10 important terms you need to know if you’re buying a house for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Looking to buy a Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buyandsellalamodanvillehomes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all Bay Area homes for sale.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling Your Bay Area Home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcma.com/api_widget/6757802779fbc05a66bfd8f78d617a92/show?post_url=cloudcma.com&amp;amp;source_url=ua&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Use our home evaluation tool.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Fixed rate mortgage:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a mortgage with a fixed rate during its term. If you have a 4.25% interest rate and a term of five, 10, 15, or 25 years, that means your rate won’t change unless you refinance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Adjustable rate mortgage (ARM):&lt;/strong&gt; This is the opposite of a fixed rate mortgage. With an ARM, you’ll have a shorter term (somewhere between five and 10 years), but once that term concludes, the rate will adjust based on the other interest rates the bank charge. This can get confusing, so I advise that you speak to a lender if you’d like more clarification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-qualified: This means you talk to a lender and give them all your paperwork (bank statements, tax documents, etc.) so they can verify whether you’re qualified to buy or not. If you make $10 an hour, you’re probably not qualified to buy a million-dollar home. If you make $1,000 an hour, you probably are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Conventional loans:&lt;/strong&gt; This is one of those loans that typically carries with it a 30-year mortgage or something similar. There are many loan products out there, so if you don’t have a high credit score, you generally won’t be able to qualify for a conventional loan—you need a minimum 650 FICO credit score so apply. The average down payment for a first-time homebuyer is only 5%, though, so there’s no need to worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. FHA loan:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a great loan for anyone who’s gone through some credit dings. The FHA stands for Federal Housing Administration. With this loan, you can put down a minimum of 3.5%. You will have to carry mortgage insurance, but you can take that off later down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=KNOW THESE TERMS BEFORE YOU BUY A HOUSE.%20http://localhost:4000/what-10-terms-should-all-first-time.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“KNOW THESE TERMS BEFORE YOU BUY A HOUSE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Appraisal:&lt;/strong&gt; An appraisal is when a third-party company analyses your property and compares it to other comparable properties within a certain radius. The home’s condition, style of property, lot size, and a variety of other factors are taken into consideration. If you offer $250,000 for the home and the appraisal comes in at $300,000, either the purchase price must come down or you have to put another $50,000 into the deal to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Mortgage insurance:&lt;/strong&gt; Mortgage insurance exists to protect the bank. If you don’t want mortgage insurance, you need to put at least 20% down. If you don’t put at least 20% down, you’ll get anywhere from 0.03% to 1.15% mortgage insurance tacked on to your rate. There are ways around this, though, and plenty of programs out there that don’t require you to use mortgage insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Closing costs:&lt;/strong&gt; What you pay in closing costs depends on you and what third-party vendors you may have brought in for expenses, such as multiple different home inspections. You can expect your closing costs to be between 2% and 5% of your purchase price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Buying down your rate:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a certain credit score but you have a lot of cash, and you have a high interest rate because of that score, you can literally pay to buy a better interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Escrow:&lt;/strong&gt; Escrow means you’re at the signing table signing away! An escrow account is a locked account which holds the buyer’s deposit so the seller can’t pull it out and the buyer can’t spend it. The way it’s kept safe is through non-conflicting instructions from both the buyer and the seller regarding releasing that cash, usually when the deal ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about any of these terms or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 14:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-10-terms-should-all-first-time.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-10-terms-should-all-first-time.html</guid>
        
        <category>Bay Area Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Bay Area Real Estate Agent</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
